A Guide to the Perkinson Family Papers, 1824-1987
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Perkinson Family Papers, 1824-1987
The Library of Virginia
51318
1.85 cubic feet (4 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mary Glen Taylor, Richmond.
Biographical Information
John Edward Perkinson (1827-1887) served with the rank of captain in the 23rd Virginia Infantry during the Civil War. After the war, he managed his plantation in Nottoway County, Virginia. He is buried at Ward's Chapel. He married Virginia Frances Williams (1829-1883). They had three sons: Thomas Randolph Sr., John Edward "Eddie", Jr., and Bland, who died while a student at the Virginia Military Institute.
Thomas Randolph Perkinson, Sr. (1859-1931) was born in Amelia County, Virginia. He resided at "Linwood" in Nottoway County. He marrried Sallie F. Shore (1871-1950), and they lived in Danville, Virginia. Their son, Thomas Randolph Perkinson, Jr., was educated in public schools at Danville, attended Cluster Springs Academy and was graduated in 1917 from the Virginia Military Institute. He was commissioned a second lieutenant of infantry during World War I, and served overseas with the Thirtieth Infantry Division. He was married at Washington, D. C. on 7 November 1923 to Caroline Reid Boyd of Sandy Spring, Maryland, formerly of Greensboro, North Carolina.
John Edward "Eddie" Perkinson, Jr. (1861-1937) served as Superintendent of Schools of Nottoway County. He married Lizzie Fitgerald (1874-1966).
Scope and Content
Papers, 1824-1987, of the Perkinson family of Amelia and Nottoway Counties, and Danville, Virginia, including John Edward Perkinson, Sr. (1827-1887) and his sons Thomas Randolph Perkinson, Sr. (1859-1931) and John Edward Perkinson, Jr. (1861-1937). The collection includes accounts and receipts, clippings, correspondence, genealogical notes, household budgets, photographs, postcards, ration books, scrapbook, and transcriptions of wills.
Contents List
- Account Book, 1944-1957. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1839-1892. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Address Book. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Agreements. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Artwork. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bank Book. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Billfold. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Brown, Clement C. - House Specifications. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brown, Clement C. - Job Application. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Calling Cards. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cayse, John. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Clippings. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1851, 1872-1889. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1890-1920. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1921-1930. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1931-1971. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Deeds. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- "Easter Lilies" by E. Dawson. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Eastman National Business College (Poughkeepsie, NY). (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Engravings. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Estate of Lizzie Fitzgerald Perkinson. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Fee Bills. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Genealogical Notes. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Household Budgets, 1966-1971. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Household Budgets, 1973-1979. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Household Budgets, 1980-1987. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Household Budgets, 1983-1987. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Insurance. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Jackson, William F. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Membership Card - Elks. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Memorandum Books. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- National Archives (Mary Boyd Brown). (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Notes and Bills Payable, 1898-1924. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Photographs. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Postcards. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Powers of Attorney. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Program. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Promissory Notes. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Ration Books. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- "Recollections of a Refugee" by J.B. Douglas. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Resolutions. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Ribbons. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Sales Brochure - "Spring Grove Farm". (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Scrapbook. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Talk - "Happy Home School," 5 December 1942. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Tax Receipts, 1852-1891. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Trade Card. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Virginia Military Institute Appointment. (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Ward's Chapel. (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Warehouse No. 7 - Industrial Avenue, Danville. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Will of John Bland. (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Will of John Doswell. (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Will of George Washington Perkinson. (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Will of Judith Perkinson. (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Will of Thomas J. Perkinson. (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Will of David G. Williams. (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Will of Thomas Roper Williams. (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Williams, Mary E.P. (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Williamson, Hubert B. (Box 3, Folder 26)
- "Wilton". (Box 3, Folder 27)